<resources>
    <string name="app_name">"AquaHealth"</string>


    <string name="titulo_agente">"Agent"</string>
    <string name="titulo_sinais">"Gross Signs"</string>
    <string name="titulo_prevencao">"Prevention"</string>
    <string name="titulo_imagens">"Images"</string>
    <string name="atencao">"ATTENTION:"</string>


    <string name="wssv_nome">"White Spot Disease"</string>
    <string name="wssv_agente">"White spot disease is caused by a virus named White spot syndrome virus, belonging to the family Nimaviridae and genus Whispovirus. The nomenclature was approved by the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (ICTV) under deposit whose name is White spot syndrome virus."</string>
    <string name="wssv_sinais">"The infection can cause disease or not, depending on factors still poorly understood, but related to species tolerance and environmental factors. White spots embedded within the exoskeleton are the most commonly observed clinical sign, however, other diseases can cause similar white spots on the shrimp exoskeleton. High levels of color variation, predominantly reddish or pinkish discolored shrimp are seen in sick populations."</string>
    <string name="wssv_sinais_atencao">"Behavioral changes are signs that should be carefully observed, as a high mortality rate in the population can be expected."</string>
    <string name="wssv_atencao_sinal_1">"If the shrimp looks lethargic"</string>
    <string name="wssv_atencao_sinal_2">"If the color changes to pink or reddish-brown"</string>
    <string name="wssv_atencao_sinal_3">"If animals gather around the edges of crops on the water surface"</string>
    <string name="wssv_atencao_sinal_4">"If there is a rapid reduction in food consumption"</string>

    <string name="wssv_prevencao">"General management practices are the best measures for white spot virus prevention. Avoid high densities in cold seasons. Prefer to use specific pathogen free (SPF) animals or populate with PCR-negative animals. For using biosecurity water and polyculture systems with shrimp and fish."</string>
    <string name="text_saiba_mais_wssv">"More information about White Spot Disease:"</string>

    <string name="imnv_nome">"Infectious myonecrosis"</string>
    <string name="imnv_agente">"Infectious myonecrosis virus (IMNV) is a member of the Totiviridae family."</string>
    <string name="imnv_sinais">"In the acute stage of the disease, the animal presents extensive areas of white necrosis in muscles, it is possible to notice the loss of transparency in the region of the tail, which may appear necrotic and reddish in some prawns. Severely affected animals become moribund and mortality can be high and sudden after a stress event."</string>
    <string name="imnv_prevencao">"Prefer to use tested and negative animals for IMNV through the reverse polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) technique. Prefer to use specific pathogen free (SPF) animals.  If there is infection, empty the OIE and MAPA recommendations. Using resistant strains of shrimp is also a good alternative for prevention to IMNV."</string>
    <string name="text_saiba_mais_imnv">"More information about Infectious Myonecrosis:"</string>

    <string name="ihhnv_nome">"Hypodermal and Hematopoietic Necrosis"</string>
    <string name="ihhnv_agente">"Recently the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (ICTV) classified this virus within the family Parvoviridae, genus Brevidensovirus, species Penaeus stylirostris densovirus (PstDNV)."</string>

    <string name="ihhnv_sinais">"The most obvious chronic clinical sign caused by this virus is a deformed rostrum of shrimp and organisms with smaller size (runt), which has been named as Runt and Deformity Syndrome (RDS). In some cases high mortalities are frequent."</string>
    <string name="ihhnv_prevencao">"Pre - screening of IHHNV by PCR to rule out virus infection before populating tanks and nurseries. Good management practices. Animals free of specific disease may be a measure, but is not the most effective action in this case."</string>
    <string name="text_saiba_mais_ihhnv">"More information about Hipodermal and Hematopoietic Necrosis:"</string>

    <string name="nhv_nome">"Necrotizing hepatopancreatitis"</string>
    <string name="nhv_agente">"Necrotizing hepatopancreatitis is a bacterial disease caused by a gram-negative, Rickettsia-like bacterium that attacks the hepatopancreas."</string>
    <string name="nhv_sinais">"Clinical signs include: lethargy, reduced food intake, atrophied and pale hepatopancreas, anorexia, empty digestive tract, low feed conversion, reduced growth  softened exoskeleton, flaccid body, loose cuticle, darkened gills, lesions, and ulcerative cuticle."</string>
    <string name="nhv_prevencao">"According to the OIE, the best treatment for NHP is the use of antibiotics (oxytetracycline and 50% florfenicol) if the disease is detected early. It's important to detect early to avoid cannibalism and start treatment quickly. Using hydrated lime to treat bottoms of tanks reduces the incidence of NHP. Prolonged drying in the sun at the bottom of the nurseries, disinfection of equipment with calcium hypochlorite are important preventive measures. Pathogen-free animal use (SPF) is an effective preventative measure."</string>
    <string name="text_saiba_mais_nhv">"More information about Necrotizing Hepatopancreatitis:"</string>

    <string name="title_activity_doenca_scrolling">"Occupational"</string>

    <string name="equipe_nomes">"Coordinator:\n
        Dr. Lissandra Souto Cavalli (DDPA/SEAPI-RS)\n\n
        Software Development:\n
        Eduardo H. P. Pooch (UFCSPA | CNPq fellow)\n\n

        AquaHealth Team:\n
        Dr. Lissandra Souto Cavalli (DDPA/SEAPI-RS)\n
        Eduardo H. P. Pooch (UFCSPA | CNPq fellow)\n
        Dr. Silvio Cazella (UFCSPA)\n
        Dr. Maria Helena Firmino (DDPA/SEAPI-RS)\n
        Dr. Marcia Regina Stech\n
        Dr. Benito Brito (DDPA/SEAPI-RS)\n
        Dr. Kelly Tagliari Brito (DDPA/SEAPI-RS)\n
        Dr. Paulo César Abreu (FURG)\n
        Dr. Luis Alberto Romano (FURG)\n
        Dr. Arturo Sanchez-Paz (CIBNOR)
        "</string>
    <string name="icone">"Icon"</string>
    <string name="instituicoes">"INSTITUTIONS"</string>
    <string name="equipe">"Staff"</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="sobre_descricao">"The objective of AquaHealth is to bring improvements to world aquaculture through the availability of information about aquatic animal health in an agile and easy to understand way. With the development of the application, scientific information that was distributed in English and different internet sites is now available easily and offline to producers and other interested parties."</string>


    <string name="biosseguranca_intro">"Biosecurity describes measures to be taken in animal husbandry to avoid the triggering of contagious diseases in the production, contamination of the crop can lead to high animal mortality and harm to the producer. Aquaculture, biosecurity is all about creating barriers that prevent the entry of  diseases that contaminate fish or shrimp.  Prevention is the most important measure in combating contagious diseases."</string>
    <string name="title_activity_checklist">Checklist</string>
    <string name="checklist_selecione">"Select the procedures that are performed in your production and check the level of biosafety applied:"</string>
    <string name="comecar">Start</string>
    <string name="proxima">"Next"</string>
    <string name="confirmar">"Confirm"</string>
    <string name="atencao_sair">"Do you want to quit the game?"</string>
    <string name="dialog_abandonar_voltar">"The game will be canceled and all data will be lost."</string>
    <string name="dialog_yes">"Yes "</string>
    <string name="dialog_no">"No"</string>
    <string name="titulo_saiba_mais">Find out more</string>

    <string name="manual_oie">"OIE Manual \n"</string>
    <string name="logo_oie">"OIE logo"</string>

    <string name="checkbox_1">"Entry of sanitized vehicles and only one origin"</string>
    <string name="resposta_1">"• Vehicles providing shrimp transport services must be registered with a disinfection report and come from a single source without having passed through other farms. This measure prevents the introduction or dissemination of pathogens in cultivation."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_2">"Control of pests and entry of wild and domestic animals on farms"</string>
    <string name="resposta_2">"• Shrimp farms should have an Integrated Pest Control System (CIP) and a protection system to minimize the entry and residence of domestic and wild animals in the farm 's production area."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_3">"It uses post-larvae free of diseases or with health certificate"</string>
    <string name="resposta_3">"• From the sanitation point of view, the purchase of animals free of pathogens or sanitary certification is the most important aspect for the beginning of the production process in the nurseries. Ideal in the acquisition, collect samples of 100 PL's in triplicate, fix in 95% ethyl alcohol and keep them filed for confirmatory PCR analyzes in case of suspected outbreaks."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_4">"The animals are transported according to the standards and care required during the marketing"</string>
    <string name="resposta_4">"• Transportation of animals must be carried out in hygienized and proper containers, at appropriate temperature and with GTA, when applicable."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_5">"Expenditure involves care such as personal hygiene and use of PPE from the personnel involved, as well as hygiene of equipment involved"</string>
    <string name="resposta_5">"• The farm must comply with the biosafety regulations regarding the personnel involved in the operations. Equipment should be sanitized after use by spraying with the use of 100 ppm chlorinated solution."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_6">"Balanced feeding by analyzing the amount of feed and the nutritional requirements according to the life stage"</string>
    <string name="resposta_6">"• Providing a balanced diet is important for the production of healthy animals and for the development of the immune system of animals."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_7">"Conducts treatment to reduce soil organic matter in nurseries"</string>
    <string name="resposta_7">"• Organic matter may originate from plankton, organic fertilizers, remains of unconsumed feed and feces from shrimp and other animals present in the growing environment. One way to treat organic matter is the continuous and systematic use of probiotics. Avoiding dead spots inside the tanks with the adjustment of the aerators as well as the use of probiotics aid in the treatment of organic matter."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_8">"Performs monitoring and treatment of nursery water"</string>
    <string name="resposta_8">"• Monitoring, control and treatment of water is a mandatory practice on farms. The tolerable limits of the main water quality parameters should be observed."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_9">"The people involved in the production process were sufficiently trained for their functions"</string>
    <string name="resposta_9">"• Personnel involved in the activities of the shrimp farm should use specific PPE and receive training and updates for their functions."</string>

    <string name="checkbox_10">"Cleaning and sanitation is carried out on premises and after"</string>
    <string name="resposta_10">"• Cleaning and sanitizing must be carried out on site and always after an expense. Performed by trained personnel and using appropriate Personal Protective Equipment (PPE)."</string>

    <string name="acess_escudo">"Shield representing biosafety"</string>
    <string name="resultado_checklist_dicas_titulo">"Check out some tips based on your markup to increase the level of biosafety:"</string>
    <string name="sua_fazenda_esta_x_biossegura">"Your farm is x% biosecured!"</string>
    <string name="ok">"OK"</string>
    <string name="msg_share">"Learn about shrimp sanity with AquaSaúde! Available for Android in the Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=br.gov.rs.fepagro.aquasaude_camarao"</string>
    <string name="default_highscore">"You have not filled the checklist yet"</string>
    <string name="resultado_10">"Your farm is biosecure!"</string>
    <string name="sua_fazenda_esta">"Your farm is "</string>
    <string name="porcento_biossegura">"% biosecure!"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_1">"Which image is not related to the entry of pathogens?"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_2">"Which factor is not associated with the onset of diseases?"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_3">"Which of these animals has NIMV?"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_4">"Which of the images is not a biosecurity measure?"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_5">" What are the PPE that should be provided to the worker?"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_5_resposta_certa">"Glove, boot and life jacket"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_5_resposta_2">"Hat, knife, knife and jeans"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_5_resposta_3">"The employee must purchase the individual protection items"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_5_resposta_4">"Glove, boot and sunscreen"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_6">"About White Spot Syndrome, it is correct to state:"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_6_resposta_certa">"Acute phase with white spots and high mortality in a few days "</string>
    <string name="pergunta_6_resposta_2">"The pathogen is a bacterium"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_6_resposta_3">"The main symptom is reduced growth"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_6_resposta_4">"There is low mortality and high morbidity"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_7">"There are no clinical signs of infectious myonecrosis:"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_7_resposta_certa">"Liquefaction of muscles and weakened"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_7_resposta_2">"Lethargy and areas with a milky appearance in the body"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_7_resposta_3">"White spots on the cap"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_7_resposta_4">"Appearance of cooked shrimp"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_8">"What illness is not mandatory?"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_8_resposta_certa">"Herpesvirus infection"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_8_resposta_2">"White Spot Syndrome"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_8_resposta_3">"Infectious myonecrosis"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_8_resposta_4">"Necrotizing hepatopancreatitis"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_9">"There are errors in sanitary management:"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_9_resposta_certa">"Use antibiotics for viral diseases"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_9_resposta_2">"Monitoring of organic matter and soil pH"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_9_resposta_3">"Disinfection of the nursery floor between cycles with dry or hydrated lime"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_9_resposta_4">"Elimination of animal vectors"</string>

    <string name="pergunta_10">" The right action to control disease transmission on farms:"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_10_resposta_certa">"Pest control and responsible waste disposal"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_10_resposta_2">"Disposal of waste resulting from processing"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_10_resposta_3">"Allocate heads and shells for use in aquaculture"</string>
    <string name="pergunta_10_resposta_4">"Dispose of waste directly into the environment"</string>

    <string name="finalizar_jogo">"Finish game"</string>
    <string name="voc_tirou_nota">"You took note:"</string>
    <string name="descricao_jogo">"Test your knowledge on aquaculture, to start tap the button below:"</string>
    <string name="titulo_quiz">Quiz AquaHealth</string>
    <string name="titulo_email">"AquaSaúde application"</string>
    <string name="descr_imagem">"Image of Shrimp with Disease"</string>
    <string name="bibliotecas">"LIBRARIES USED"</string>
    <string name="bibliotecas_descricao">"Icons: flaticon.com \n
        Glide: github.com/bumptech/glide\n
        PhotoView: github.com/chrisbanes/PhotoView\n
        AutoFit TextView: github.com/grantland/android-autofittextview\n"</string>

    <string name="doencas">Diseases </string>
    <string name="peixes">Fish </string>
    <string name="boas_praticas">Good Practices</string>
    <string name="jogos">Games</string>
    <string name="sobre">About</string>
    <string name="contato">Contact</string>
    <string name="compartilhar">Share</string>
    <string name="fale_conosco">Contact Us</string>
    <string name="principais_doencas">Main shrimp diseases:</string>
    <string name="preencher_checklist">Fill Checklist</string>
    <string name="rever_resultado">Review last result</string>
    <string name="maior_nota">Your highest score:</string>

</resources>